I'm throwing a birthday party.
You should come.
You're kinda easy to talk to lately.
Well...
I did decide not to lie to you.
I said that out loud.
H-Hinazuki!
Laters!
See you tomorrow!
This is where I last saw Hinazuki 18 years ago.
Her body was only found
after the snow melted,
but she went missing sometime in March. What day?
If I can figure that out,
I can prevent her kidnapping.
Nakanishi Aya.
Sugita Hiromi.
Right, Hiromi was killed, too.
But only Hinazuki was ten years old.
So her birthday hadn't yet passed
when she went missing in March.
Which means that X-Day is somewhere
between March 1st and her birthday.
Ow!
Apparently the boys are competing in pairs.
Oh, that sounds like fun.
I bet Hamada's gonna get the best time.
Probably.
Hamada-kun!
Ice hockey team, represent!
Kick some butt, Hamada!
Please shut up.
Show 'em who's boss!
Go!
Don't expect me to go easy on you.
Got it.
Hamada's a starter on the ice hockey team
that won the national championship.
I do remember racing him at some point.
Fujinuma's going up against Hamada.
Poor guy.
Wish him luck, Hinazuki.
Go on, Hinazuki.
Think you can win, Fujinuma?
I'll give it my all.
I see. Well, good luck.
On your marks...
Get set...
Crap!
C'mon, Satoru!
What're you doing, Hamada?!
He's fast!
Fujinuma must've jumped the gun.
Am I really allowed to win?
Is there any point to me winning?
This guy does his best and practices hard every day.
It's obvious who should win.
Score!
See? Hamada did win in the end.
That was awesome!
Satoru pushed Hamada
all the way! That's incredible!
Right, Kenya?
Fujinuma!
I hate punks like you!
Satoru!
That was a close one, huh?
Shaddup!
What's his deal?
Seriously. Getting mad just 'cause he nearly lost.
It's fine.
I remember now.
I hate punks like you!
I ended up making the same
mistake I made 18 years ago.
Wait up, Hinazuki!
Hamada was too fast for me after all.
Oh.
Hey...
When's your birthday?
What's wrong?
You said you wouldn't lie to me.
Sorry.
I felt like today was meant to be Hamada's day.
Oh.
Look...
It's fine.
We're both fakes and liars.
Let's head home, Satoru-kun.
Sorry, I forgot something. Go on ahead!
What's up, Satoru?
Yashiro-sensei...
U-Uh...
Is this about Kayo?
He's got good intuition.
I wanted to know her birthday.
I'm sorry.
Is that so?
You've become good friends with her lately, huh?
I don't know about that.
You didn't ask her?
I told her when my birthday was,
but she wouldn't tell me hers.
Ah, I get it now.
See for yourself.
What exactly do you "get"?
The same birthday as me?
I get it now.
Thanks.
Well, Kayo's a bit shy, so she probably found
it hard to mention you shared birthdays.
Don't let that get to you, though.
Celebrate it with her.
Will do.
Well, goodbye.
Satoru.
Too bad about the race today.
Whatever you do, always give it your all.
The same goes with Kayo, too.
Right!
Yashiro Gaku.
He must be around my age at this time.
He's got a sharp, discerning eye.
I now know when X-Day is.
It's March 1st.
11 days from now.
I have to make up with Hinazuki first.
Huh? She's not here.
Satoru-kun!
Yuuki-san!
Y-You seem to have made l-lots of friends.
Good for you.
He's 23 years old at this time,
which means he's younger than me.
I owe it all to you.
No, you don't!
I-It's all because y-you worked up the courage.
Wh-When you want to have fun with people,
th-they usually get the message.
His stammering and gentle nature
are just how I remember. He's a nice guy.
Yuuki-san, do you know Hinazuki Kayo?
Kayo-chan? Yeah, I know her.
That was quick.
The girl who's always at the park by herself, right?
I've talked to her a bunch of times.
Are you two classmates?
Yep.
Oh, really?
Jun! Let's eat!
You go ahead. I'll eat later.
Isn't it a bit early for dinner?
We start really early in the morning.
I work at my dad's catering service from 4 a.m.
4 a.m.? Really?
Yeah. Only until noon, though.
Ah...
Since I always saw him hanging around in
the afternoon, I just assumed he was unemployed.
Now that I'm 29, I can tell he's making an effort
to use standard Japanese in front of me.
Kids tend to find this manner
of speech credible and mature.
How did he talk to you?
Did it give you the impression he was a nice guy?
They put out a papercraft
tournament special recently.
U-Uh, I-I got those from someone,
s-so I couldn't th-throw them away.
Don't worry. It doesn't bother me.
Was there anything in his room
that made you feel uneasy?
Oh, I should get going.
Okay.
Satoru-kun, you've matured quite a bit.
You think so?
Yeah!
Shiratori Jun.
In May 2006, he's sitting on death row.
He's maintained his innocence ever since the initial hearing.
I really can't believe that
Yuuki-san would murder anyone.
If no crimes take place, there won't be any suspects.
Just you wait, Yuuki-san.
I swear I'll...
She's still not home?
This place is a mess.
What's this?
Gloves!
Don't tell me...
Hinazuki!
Don't look at me.
Close the door.
N-No! If you stay here...
Stay away!
What's the matter, Kayo?
You cooped in here by yourself again?
This bitch...
This bitch!
Get in the house, quick.
Hey!
How did she get those bruises?
Tell him, Kayo.
I fell.
I couldn't find the words
to respond to Hinazuki's sad lie.
Her eyes wouldn't look my way anymore.
Come on, Kayo. Cool it down!
If you don't get that face
of yours healed by Monday,
I'll get all the blame!
Hey.
Leave some ice for me.
She's not here yet.
Morning, Satoru.
Morning.
So cold.
Here's how you calculate the radius.
The circumference is the diameter multiplied by pi,
so if you divide by pi instead,
you'll get the diameter,
which you can divide by two...
Hinazuki...
It's okay. Take your seat.
All right, who wants to come up here and solve this?
How about you, Satou?
Who, me?
Come on, it's simple.
We're collecting the school lunch money!
I have to change the future.
Put it in this box.
If you forgot to bring yours today,
you have until tomorrow!
The reason Kayo's often late
or absent on Mondays, huh?
Do you have an idea, Satoru?
Because her mother beats her on Saturdays.
Oh, so you noticed.
You knew about it?
Well, uh...
What is it? Tell me!
I was wondering if I should
tell the other students or not.
You know how Kayo's cut off
from the rest of the class, right?
If they find out she's being abused on top of that,
everyone might discriminate against her.
No way!
No, Satoru, I know you wouldn't.
So I'll tell you.
Keep it a secret from the others.
Got it.
Honestly, we started suspecting
Kayo's mother around May last year.
But as of now, no concrete steps
have been taken to deal with it.
Why?
Her mother ends up covering it up well.
The Child Welfare Center has visited
them three times as of last month,
but she has good intuition, because each time they came, she was out with Kayo.
They haven't been able to question them yet.
Useless hacks.
I said that out loud.
Yeah.
I've met the mother a few times.
Kayo's definitely being abused.
All we need is confirmation
from the Child Welfare Center.
We'll free Kayo from her mother as soon as possible.
Their preparations are that far along, huh?
But if and when that happens,
Kayo won't be in this class anymore.
As long as Hinazuki is saved, I don't care.
Hurry, Sensei.
Yashiro must be waiting
for spring break to take action.
But it'll be too late by then!
Step on it, damn it!
Sit down already!
Oh, shit.
The lunch money is gone.
29 years old and I've gotta
get caught up in something like this?
Sir.
What is it?
I lost everyone's lunch money.
I don't think he lost it.
Somebody must've stolen it.
Like Hinazuki-san, maybe.
Wait. What makes you say that?
I mean, she hasn't paid for her lunches.
And I'm sure only someone
who's poor would steal the money.
She's probably right!
Did you take it, Hinazuki?
Goddamn brat...
We'll find out once we check everyone's bags.
I agree!
Man, I wanna eat already.
Aren't you gonna look for it?
Why bother? I didn't take it.
Search your neighbors' bags, too!
You took it, didn't you?
Don't be stupid.
Come on, find the thief!
Nothing here.
It's gotta be Hinazuki, right?
Obviously!
She's poor!
Found it.
It was Hinazuki!
It was someone who's poor!
Kayo's the thief!
See? I was right!
Shut up!
So what if she's poor or starving?
Hinazuki would never steal from anybody!
I bet it was you.
You know, anybody could've taken it
from Satoru's desk and planted it there.
Class, Kayo's on duty today, so there's
nothing strange about her having the money.
Misato, Satoru. This ends here, okay?
Let's have lunch.
School will be closing shortly...
Well, this is awkward.
Thanks for earlier, Fujinuma.
No problem.
She was saying some really awful things.
When we were in third grade,
she kept making fun of my pencils.
so I threw her prized
mechanical pencil out the window.
She's hated me ever since.
Though the feeling's mutual.
But this one time,
she invited me to a Christmas party.
She just wanted to show off her big Christmas tree.
It was so pretty.
I remember now.
Hey...
How about we go see one today?
See what?
A Christmas tree.
Are you stupid?
Here.
They're just cotton gloves.
But we're going up a hill, so it'll be cold.
I never said I'd go.
I used to ski and bobsled here all the time.
I even saw red foxes every now and then.
There they are!
Wh-Whoa!
I remembered the red foxes circling around my feet.
But I saw them by myself 18 years ago.
Nobody believed me when I told them.
Think they're a couple?
They must be.
I'm in luck today.
The clouds have cleared up.
We're here.
Look, it's a Christmas tree.
Right?
Are you stupid? It's February.
Let's come back here in the summer.
To see this Christmas tree.
Are you stupid?